Hello, when we talk about term insurance or pure
life insurance,
one thing that everyone says is that after my
death, my family should not have any
financial gain,
but term insurance is
something that brings financial security to our family in our absence. Now I am taking a term insurance.
I have taken term insurance for a period of 30 years. In the
meantime, if I die, I will
cover my family's income
or if I have any liabilities, loans or other liabilities. Term insurance should be used only to cover them. We should not consider term insurance as a savings or investment instrument. We should take term insurance only to keep our family
financially stable.
So the
second question that comes to your mind is which is the
best term insurance. When
I went to select the best term insurance, I compared
many term insurance or
life insurance companies and
chose two or three
companies from them.  When I selected and compared it,
I came to know about a plan called Axis Max Life's Smart Total Elite Protection.
This plan has many features.
Two or
three unique features make it attractive.
Another thing about it is the attractive premiums. Then, if we
talk about claim settlement,
Axis Max Life Insurance is also a company that has a good claim settlement ratio above the average in the industry.
Today, in this video, I will discuss
about the plan called Step by Axis Max Life Insurance. What are the
features that come in this plan? How to
purchase this plan? How does
its claim pay out come?
We are
going to discuss in this video. Hello, my
name is Satya Espy. I am an insurance advisor. I have been
working as an industrial advisor since 2018. My hometown is
Ernakulam, Aluva. Smart Total
Elite Protection.
Before talking about the plan, let's see why I
chose Axis Max Life Insurance. If we
look at the average claim settlement ratio of Axis Max Life, it
is 9917%. This is the average of the claim settlement ratio for the last three years. So, it is
a claim settlement ratio that is higher than the industry average.
Now, let's look at Axis Max Life's complaints per 10,000 claims,
that is, how many claims are subject to complaints after 10,000 claims are received. The
industry average is
17 claims, that is, after 10,000 claims are
received, 17 of them are subject to
complaints. This is the industry
average, but if we take the case of Axis Life,
they only
receive complaints for three claims. Now, if we take a premium of this, when we
compare the top brands in the industry, it is comparatively
Axis Max Life's Step plan is also a plan with low premium. So,
today we will
discuss more about the Step plan in this video.
What are the major benefits that come in it?
We are also discussing some unique things in it.
Plus, let's discuss how to take this policy. The major
benefit in this is the death benefit. In term
insurance or pure term
insurance, if
we take a term insurance for a term of 30 years, after
we
die in those 30 years, the insurer returns that sum to our nominee as a lump sum
or as an annual income or as a
monthly income.
Term insurance is called pure death benefit.
But this plan also has some additional advantages.
Before that, let's see how to pay the premium.
We can pay the premium in three ways.
One is by whole.  Term means
we can pay in regular premium i.e.
I am
taking the policy at the age of 30. If I
want this term coverage
till the age of 60, regular payment option is available in which we can pay the premium regularly every month
or every year from 30 to 60 years. Single
premium payment option is also available
in this i.e.
we pay the premium till the age of 60 in the first year itself.
Now there is a third option which is
Limited Premium Payment
Term i.e. we can pay the premium for the first five years, 10 years,
12 years or even 15 years
but
we get coverage till the age of 60.
This is what I call Limited Premium
Payment Term.
I always tell my customers or those who know me to choose
Limited Premium Payment Term
because we are in our 30s
or 40s.  When
we take term insurance at an early age, we will have a stable income for the first 10
or 15 years. If
we pay this premium at that time,
we can keep our remaining term safe.
Now, if we
talk about claim payout,
we can also come up with three methods. First,
we can take it as lump sum. Now, let's say that one
crore is our death benefit.
After the death of the insured,
we can choose this plan in such a way that the total one crore amount goes to our nominee. Or, there
is also a method in this policy where we get it as a monthly or annual annuity. So, after we die,
we can get one crore
as a monthly or annual income. We can also
do it in such a way that
we can select lump sum and
monthly scheme together.
We can get 50% lump sum together and the
remaining amount as an annuity.
We can choose this policy in such a way that
Now
I will tell you about some of the unique benefits that come in this policy. The
first of them is the ACI
Accelerated Critical Illness
Benefit. Normally,
all companies
offer critical illness benefits, but I will tell you
about the Accelerated Critical Illness, which is a little unique. If
we add an ACI rider to a 50 lakhs policy, then
our basic sum insured is one crore. If
we
suffer from any critical illness,
50 lakhs will be given to us first. The
remaining 50 lakhs will be given to
us at the time of death.
This is the ACI rider.
Why am I suggesting this? In this, the premium is
very
low compared to the remaining critical illness rider. In this policy itself, the
critical illness rider
is another option available to us, but it is
additional.  The additional sum insured
comes in the premium. Here we
get the accelerated amount. So both these
options are available to us in this policy.
Now the
second feature that I find unique is the
special exit value.
This is an inbuilt
thing. It is not something that is available in the rider or extra
premium. If
we take a term of more than 30 years,
for example, let's assume that we
take a term of 40 years.
After 30 years,
we can exit this policy. We will
get the total premium excluding GST back. But
we cannot exit for the last four years of the term.
So no matter
how many terms we take for more than 30 years,
we will get this rider. This is not a rider, it is actually an
inbuilt benefit.
So we do not need term insurance. Even if our
liability is all over,
we can exit it and get the total
premium excluding GST.  We
get GST back. This
is a feature found only in this plan of Max Life. Now the
third
unique benefit found in this is the cover continuity
benefit. Normally, if we do not pay the premium during the grace
period, that is,
after the premium is due, we
get a grace period of one month. If we do not pay the premium during that time, the
company does not cover us.
But in this policy, if
we do not pay the premium for any 12 months after the first three years,
that risk is
assumed by the company. If we do not pay the premium for 12 months, the
company assumes that risk even if the premium is due. If
we pay the premium after 12 months, that coverage
can continue as usual. This is
most beneficial for
corporate employees. For some
reason, they
change their jobs or have been out of work for
a while. If the
premium is not paid for 12 months, they
get continuity of coverage.
This is in this policy.  This is
a unique
benefit that I have come across. All other companies
only give a grace period of 30 days, after which
the policy
becomes lapsed. So, even if we pay the premium within 30 days, if
something happens to us during the grace period, we will not
get coverage. The
fourth benefit that I have come across
is the terminal illness cover.
That is, if we are affected by a terminal
illness, we
become bedridden. We
cannot do anything alone. If we are in a situation where we are almost facing death,
it is called terminal illness. If such a
situation arises, we will be given a claim up
to one crore upfront.
This is also an accelerated
matter. Now, if we
take a basic sub-insured policy of two crores, if
we are affected by a terminal illness,
we will first get one crore and then
after death.  After that, the nominee will get one crore.
This is how this policy is designed.
This is also an
inbuilt thing. While many other
companies give it at an additional cost,
here we get it as an inbuilt thing.
Another unique
benefit that I have
seen in this is instant pay out on claim
intimation. When we have a death and we intimation the claim, within one
working
day, once we have submitted the correct documents, within one
working day, we will be given the first two
lakh rupees as claim pay out. The
remaining amount will be given
after the proper investigation.
All other companies
take an investigation and sometimes there are investigations that go for 45
days or two months, three
months, sometimes up to one year. After that, the pay out
or claim
amount will be given to this nominee. But in this
case, we have to first
intimation and then we  The
nominee gets Rs 2 lakhs as soon as the documents are submitted. The
remaining amount
will be given after the investigation. This is also a unique
benefit. Most other
companies or 99% of the
companies do not give this benefit.
They pay out only after the investigation.
Like all other companies,
we also get added advantages.
Riders come with a few things.
Critical Illness As I
said earlier, apart from Accelerator
Critical Illness, we also get
Normal Critical Illness Rider.
We can
cover extra sum assured in extra premium. Accelerator is a way to cover extra sum assured in extra premium.
Even if it is a critical illness, we have to
pay extra premium. It comes
as a rider. There are about 40
critical illnesses in this
critical illness rider and in the
accident critical illness rider.  It
covers the prevention of
critical illness rider. After adding this, if
we pay an extra premium, if
we get any
critical illness or
disability, the
company will
waive off all the premiums from that day onwards. We can take that in this
policy as an extra premium. The
third thing is
accident coverage, that is, if we
die due to an accident,
we get an extra sum insured. We can
take that in an extra premium.
So, if we talk about this policy, there are about
ten unique benefits
or riders in it.
We have discussed all the major riders here.
Now, when we
talk about this plan, the most important
thing to say is the premium.
I have taken an illustration of my age
here. If a
29-year-old person takes
term insurance coverage until the age of 65, if he
takes a limited premium payment term for the first 10 years,
his premium will be  ₹25000
plus tax comes to almost ₹30000,
which means that the amount I have to pay
or the
amount he has to pay
is three lakhs in total, but the
coverage he gets is up to one crore.
So no matter how you look at it,
term insurance is always a beneficial coverage for the insured.
Term insurance is something that should be taken out mandatory by any income-generating person. Term insurance is not only a
scheme that we can pay monthly, but also has
options to increase and decrease the payment term.
Now, when we compare its premium with
other companies,
we can consider it
as a nominal premium
because when we compare it with ICICI Prudential
or HDFC Life, the premium is comparatively low.
Life has put this up so that
you can know more about term insurance.
To know more about the plan called Step by Axis Max Life, you
can also contact me directly. If you have any doubts about this plan, you can
comment in the comment box below. If
you found this
video useful, please
share it with your friends and family. To know more details about health
insurance
or term insurance, you
can follow Finsuraksha. My name is
Satyajit S. Bye. I am your own
insurance advisor. Thank you. Greetings.